Guide to the Lawrence Lee Papers, 1920-1978 SC.1978.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Lawrence Lee Papers
1920-1978
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Lee, Lawrence
SC.1978.01
9 Linear Feet (18 boxes)
Lawrence Lee was a published writer of poetry, drama, fiction and essays. At the time of his death in 1978, he was a contributing columnist to the Pittsburgh Press and had been a member of the University of Pittsburgh English Department for 31 years. The Lee papers include manuscripts, clippings, and personal correspondence, as well as copies of published books and magazine articles written by Lee, autographed editions by other contemporary authors, and association copies.
Biography
Lawrence Lee, professor emeritus of the University of Pittsburgh, was a published writer of poetry, drama, fiction and essays. Born in 1903 in Gadsden, Alabama, Lee was best known for his lyrical poetry. Notable publications include Lee's poetry on the life of Thomas Jefferson in Monticello and Other Poems (1937) and The Tomb of Thomas Jefferson and Other Poems (1940). Other notable publications include Lee's Pittsburgh pieces: Prometheus in Pittsburgh (1952), The American as Faust (1965), and "The Cathedral" (1966). Lee worked variously as an editor, instructor, and contributor to literary journals and newspapers. Lee was editor of the Virginia Quarterly Review from 1938-42, and contributed to publications such as The Sewanee Review, The Georgia Review, The Michigan Quarterly Review, The Lyric, and The Classical World. He was an instructor in English, French, and literature at various universities. The largest part of his teaching career was spent at the University of Pittsburgh. At the time of his death on October 4, 1978, he was a contributing columnist to the Pittsburgh Press and had been a member of the University of Pittsburgh English Department for 31 years.
Scope and Content Notes
The Lawrence Lee Papers consist primarily of manuscripts and typescripts of Lee's works, as well as correspondence, newspaper clippings, and books related to Lee's writing and teaching work. The collection includes multiple draft versions of Lee's writings, including a range of holograph notebooks and corrected typescripts. Lee's correspondence includes exchanges with editors and contemporary writers. Audio recordings of selected Lee works are included, as well as a small number of photographs and non-textual items, such as award plaques and graduation regalia. A small number of personal papers related to Lee's teaching career, home, and graduate coursework is also included.
Books from Lee's personal collection are shelved with the manuscripts and include a range of annotated volumes, presentation copies, and rare books. A full inventory of books and journals donated with Lee's collection is available in the Special Collections Department.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into three series:
Series I. Writings, 1925-1978
Series II. Correspondence, 1924-1978
Series III. Personal Papers, 1920-1978
Existence and Location of Originals
The Lee collection includes both newspaper clippings and a small number of journals and newspapers. Lee's newspaper clippings have been photocopied for preservation purposes and include citation information. Originals have not been retained. For journals or newspapers containing Lee writings, pages containing his work have been photocopied for the collection (see Series I: Subseries 7), along with citation information. A complete inventory of books and journals donated with the collection is available in the Special Collections Department.
Physical Characteristics & Technical Requirements
In addition to paper materials, the Lee collection also includes 13 audio reels and one cassette tape recording readings and performances of Lee's works. Please see Special Collections staff for more information on how to listen to this material.
Previous Citation
Lawrence Lee Papers, 1920-1978, SC.1978.01, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Acquisition Information
Gift of Lawrence Lee's family in 1978.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Clippings (Information artifacts); Manuscripts for publication; Poetry; Personal papers; Correspondence; Manuscripts (Document genre); Pittsburgh (Pa.); College teachers -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Poets, American -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Poets, American -- 20th century; Pittsburgh press; Typescripts; University of Pittsburgh -- Faculty; Cathedral of Learning (Pittsburgh, Pa.); University of Pittsburgh. Department of English -- Faculty; Lee, Lawrence
- Writings, 1925-1978; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Series consists of typescript and manuscript drafts of Lee's poetry, prose, drama, essays and lectures ranging from 1925 through 1978. The series also includes newspaper clippings and reviews of Lee by other authors. The collection includes 13 audio reels and one audio cassette. Audio material records Lee reading his poetry as well as a performance of his dramatic poem, "The American as Faust." Correspondence accompanying Lee's manuscripts has been kept with the title to which it refers; for additional, general correspondence, see Series II.
  The series is arranged into seven subseries by genre: Poetry, Prose, Drama, Press, Literary Essays and Lectures, and Audio Recordings. Subseries are arranged by title and chronology.
  - Poetry, 1925-1976; 1.
    This subseries consists of typescript and manuscript drafts of Lee's poetry. Correspondence accompanying Lee's manuscripts has been kept with the title to which it refers; for additional, general correspondence, see Series II. The subseries is arranged chronologically and by title, with undated material at the end.
    - "Earlier Manuscripts", 1925-1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Poem - "A Hawk at Cuckoo Tavern" MS, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Tomb of Thomas Jefferson" MS, 1926-1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - A Flight of Geese bound TS with interleaved MS poems, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Summer Goes On MS, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Summer Goes On Galleys, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Monticello and Other Poems MS, 1933-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Helen's Three Daughters musical score, 1936, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Poems MS, 1939-1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Poems: Notebook Two holograph notebook, 1944-1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - American School of Classical Studies notebook of holograph poems, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Poems MS, 1963-1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Poems III holograph notebook, 1963-1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "The Cathedral: In Memoriam - Stanton Chapman Crawford" MS, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "The Cathedral" - printing for Phi Beta Kappa initiation, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "The Cathedral" Dedication, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "The Cathedral" music correspondence (Prof. Nathan Davis), 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "The Cathedral: In Memoriam - Stanton Chapman Crawford" printing for slate dedication, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "The Cathedral" Phi Beta Kappa correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Cathedral Poets I correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Cathedral Poets I front matter, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Cathedral Poets I proofs, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
    - Cathedral Poets I review, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - The Cretan Flute correspondence, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Note regarding Oct 15th recording of The Cretan Flute & Poems, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Litany for the New World to Rubén Dario holograph notebook, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Litany for the New World MS, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Litany for the New World TS and corrected Virginia Quarterly Review reprint, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Litany for the New World correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Litany for the New World 1776-1976, Killybegs, and Other Poetry corrected TS, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "Killibegs" correspondence, 1968-1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - "Killybegs" TS, circa 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Balletomania staging with Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre and San Francisco Ballet, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - La Dame a la Licorne correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Between the Morning and the Evening Star TS, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "Pittsburgh in Poetry" and other poems at Three Arts Festival, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Poems IV holograph notebook, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Horse of Selene correspondence, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Horse of Selene review, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - New poems MS, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Cathedral Poets II correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cathedral Poets II completed MS, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Cathedral Poets II TS, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Cathedral Poets II galley proofs, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - New poems TS (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - "Pittsburgh the Dynamic City" (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Prose, 1958-1977; 2.
    This subseries consists of typescript and manuscript drafts of Lee's prose. Correspondence accompanying Lee's manuscripts has been kept with the title to which it refers; for additional, general correspondence, see Series II. The subseries is arranged chronologically and by title, with undated material at the end.
    - "Husbands and Strangers" from Saturday Evening Post, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "The Fishing Pole Flute" TS, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - To What Green Altar esquisse for a short novel, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "Desmond, The New Baby, and the Penny Pig" TS, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Cockcrow at Night reviews, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Cockcrow at Night and Other Stories sales and promotion (Boxwood Press), 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Cockcrow at Night correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Cockcrow at Night correspondence with London publishers, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "Every Bridge Leads to Somewhere", 1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "Melissa", 1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "Fancy Ham has an Idea", 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - The Sound of Locusts esquisse for a short novel (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - The Sound of Locusts TS (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
    - "Of Love and Mercy" TS (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "The Sisters Keszkemethy" TS (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - "Good-bye, My Son" TS (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - The Nameless are My Brothers bound TS (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - An Alliance of Strangers TS (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
    - Desperate Comedians and Other Stories TS (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
    - "The Dusty Fountain" TS (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - "The Ripening Fruit" TS (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - "Marauding Crows" TS (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - "Time was Near Morning" TS (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - French Poetry MS (Box 6, Folder 10-12)
  - Drama, 1941-1965; 3.
    This subseries consists of typescript and manuscript drafts of Lee's drama. Correspondence accompanying Lee's manuscripts has been kept with the title to which it refers; for additional, general correspondence, see Series II. The subseries is arranged chronologically and by title, with undated material at the end.
    - "The Voice of the Furies" MS ("The Ghost of Peter Jones"), 1941 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "The Voice of the Furies" TS and correspondence, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "South Revisited" Script as broadcast, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Moby Dick Script and comments, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Moby Dick Script with corrections, circa 1947 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "Prometheus in Pittsburgh" MS, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - "Prometheus in Pittsburgh" program, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - "Prometheus in Pittsburgh" script, circa 1953 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "Prometheus in Pittsburgh" photographs of TV production, circa 1953 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "Lincoln Portrait" with Pittsburgh Symphony, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - "American as Faust" advertising, circa 1965 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - "American as Faust" reviews and correspondence, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "American as Faust" publication correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - "American as Faust" TS, circa 1962 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "American as Faust" revised script and reviews, 1959-1962 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "American as Faust" esquisse and review, 1956-1957, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "American as Faust" script and reviews, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - "American as Faust" clippings, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - "American as Faust" for 1959 Convocation (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - "American as Faust" schedule and staging, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - "American as Faust" programs, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - "American as Faust" TS, circa 1959 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - "American as Faust" TS, circa 1957 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - "American as Faust" TS, circa 1957 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - "American as Faust" TS with corrections, circa 1957 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - "American as Faust" MS, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Press, 1932-1975; 4.
    This subseries consists of typescript and manuscript drafts of Lee's newspaper and magazine articles. Correspondence accompanying Lee's manuscripts has been kept with the title to which it refers; for additional, general correspondence, see Series II. The subseries is arranged chronologically and by title, with undated material at the end.
    - Reviews of Lee's work, 1932-1968 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Reviews of Lee, 1933-circa 1940 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Clippings of reviews, 1933-1975 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Clippings of reviews from Richmond News Leader, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Reviews by and of Lee, 1937-1962 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Book reviews by Lee, 1945-1961 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, 1959-1965 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Reviews of Lee, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Pittsburgh Press TS, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
    - Newsletters and clippings, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Pittsburgh Press articles, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Pittsburgh Press articles, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Pittsburgh Press articles, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Pittsburgh Press articles, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Pittsburgh Sunday Press articles and responses, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Literary Essays and Lectures, 1961-1978; 5.
    This subseries consists of typescript and manuscript drafts of Lee's literary essays and public lectures. Correspondence accompanying Lee's manuscripts has been kept with the title to which it refers; for additional, general correspondence, see Series II. The subseries is arranged chronologically and by title, with undated material at the end.
    - "A Crisis in Integrity" drafts, correspondence, and notes, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "A Crisis in Integrity" responses, clippings and correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - WQED "Robert Frost" broadcast TS, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Irish pamphlets (Dolmen Press, Yeats Summer School, "American as Faust," Kennys Bookshops), 1967-1968, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "Yeats' Use of Myth" TS, circa 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Yeats International Summer School correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "The Voices of Poetry" corrected TS, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "Notes for the Oncoming Generation" drafts, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - "Notes for the Oncoming Generation" correspondence, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - "Notes for the Oncoming Generation" correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - "Notes for the Oncoming Generation" clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - "Education and Social Ethics" speech for Robert Morris College, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - "Writing and Society" speech for the Women's Press Club, April 16, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - "Our Families and Social Change" speech for Woman's Club of Mt. Lebanon, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - "Responsibilities of Being Southern" speech for the Southern Club, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - "While You are Young" TS, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - "Business: Has it the Capability for Crisis Leadership?" speech for Rotary Club of Pittsburgh, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - "Understanding Life through Literature" speech for Beta Phi Mu society, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - "The Moral Responsibilities of Citizenship" speech for Allegheny County League of Women Voters, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - "A Memorial for Wayne Davis", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - "The Teacher's Heritage" speech for Phi Delta Kappa, California State College (Pa.), 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - "Making a World in which to Live" speech for Allegheny General Hospital, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Candle in the Dark TS (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The Tragic Thread: A Book of Literary Essays corrected TS (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
    - "Notes on the Nature of Poetry" TS (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Poetry and Reverence" MS (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "Poetry and Nationality" TS (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Audio Recordings, 1958-1968; 6.
    This subseries includes 13 audio reels and one audio cassette. Audio material records Lee reading his poetry as well as a performance of his dramatic poem, "The American as Faust." The subseries is arranged chronologically and by title, with undated material at the end. If you intend to use these audio materials, please contact the staff at the Special Collections Department prior to your visit to see if the proper equipment is available.
    - "American as Faust" reels (copy), 1958 (Box 12, Reel 1-3)
    - "American as Faust" reels (copy), 1958 (Box 12, Reel 4-6)
    - "Literary Varieties" and "Poetry – Lawrence Lee", 1958 (Box 12, Reel 7)
    - Lawrence Lee Reading from His Poetry, 1968 (Box 12, Reel 8-10)
    - [Unknown] reels (Box 12, Reel 11-13)
    - Cathedral Slate Dedication (Box 12, Cassette 14)
  - Publications, 1927-1978; 7.
    This subseries contains preservation copies from the journals and compilations that Lee donated with his papers. Photocopies have been made of the articles, poems, and other writings by Lee, as well as reviews of Lee's work, that were contained in these publications. See Special Collections for a full list of donated journals and books, including Lee's monographs and annotated or signed copies of other authors' works. The subseries is arranged chronologically and by title, with undated material at the end.
    - from The Third Book of Modern Verse, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - from The Best Poems of 193 3 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - from Icarus, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - from The Best Poems of 1940 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - from The Best Poems of 1942 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - from Reader's Scope, April 1946 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - from Reader's Scope, August 1946 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - from Reader's Scope, September 1946 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - from Reader's Scope, January 1947 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - from Hidden Streams, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - from The Jefferson Reader, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - from Saturday Evening Post, 1953, 1958-1959 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - from Anthology of Magazine Verse, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - from Argosy, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - from The Pittsburgh Press, 1961, 1970-1976 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - from Serendipity, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - from The New York Times Book Review, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - from The New York Times, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - from The Argonaut, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - from The Best American Short Stories, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - from Poems from the Virginia Quarterly Review, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - from Chinese Lyrics from the 8th to the 12th Centuries, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - from National Review, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - from Typo Graphic, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - from Social Service Outlook, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - from Problems in Effective Cross-Cultural Interaction, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - from The Lyric, 1971-1972, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - from Allegheny General Hospital Annual Report, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - from University Times, 1973, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - from Literary Tabloid, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - from Pittsburgh Renaissance, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - from Serenity, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - from Pitt News, August 1976 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - from International Biographical Centre Magazine review of Lee, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 34)
- Correspondence, 1924-1978; II.
  Series II contains personal and professional correspondence from 1924 through 1978. The series includes correspondence with editors, publishers, and other writers of the period. The bulk of the material consists of correspondence with Dr. J.S. Wilson and Ralph Buchsbaum. The collection also includes letters from major figures such as Robert Frost, Sherwood Anderson, F. Scott Fitzgerald. The series is arranged alphabetically, by agency or author's last name. Additional correspondence, kept by Lee alongside specific manuscripts, is located in Series I.
  - List of Letters Owned by L. Lee, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Letters from Autograph Collection, 1929-1962 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Autographed Banknote (Charles Lindbergh and others), 1945 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1964-1977 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Anderson, Sherwood, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Aswell, Edward (Estate of Thomas Wolfe), 1949 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Baxter, Dr. Frank, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Benet, William Rose (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Boxwood Press (Ralph Buchsbaum), 1962-1976 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - British Museum (Sir John Pope-Hennessy), 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Cabell, James Branch, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Chen, Shih-chuan, 1967-1974 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - The Classical World, 1965-1967 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Coutsis, Elias - Correspondence and Poem, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Crow, Charles, 1965-1975 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - De la Mare, Walter, 1941-1946 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Dolmen Press (Liam Miller / Eileen Power), 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Durham, Mildred, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Eliot, T.S. (Faber and Faber), 1944 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Fitzgerald, F. Scott, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Ford, Ford Madox, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Frost, Robert (with TS poem, The Silken Tent), 1938 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Glasgow, Ellen, 1933-1938 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Haskins, Dr. John, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Harvard University, 1968-1973 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Henn, Tom and Enid, 1972-1976 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - International Academy of Poets, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Jeffers, Robinson, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Kent State University, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Ketchum, Carlton, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Kostelanetz, Andre, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Lardas, Konstantinos, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Larry, R. Heath, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Lawrence, Frieda, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Library of Congress, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - The Literary Tabloid (Iris Papazian), 1975 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - The Literary Tabloid, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - The Lyric, 1970-1972 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Macken, Janine S. (re: D.H. Lawrence), 1948, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Martin, Mrs. Fred E., 1974-1978 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Masefield, John (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Mc--, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - McFee, William, 1927 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Meacham, Harry, 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Mencken, H.L., 1933-1936 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Morgan, Charles, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - O'Casey, Sean, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Oxford UP, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Petrov, Nicholas (Pittsburgh Ballet), 1978 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Pittsburgh Press, 1970-1976 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Pittsburgh Press responses, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Poetry Society of Virginia, 1969-1975 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Posvar, Wesley (Chancellor, University of Pittsburgh) and Powers, David, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Riley, Ruth, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Robinson, E.A., 1928, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 10)